Welcome to Module 6 In this module
we are going to move from writing
small pieces of Python code toward organizing
larger programs in a cleaner and more
reusable way Up to this point you
have worked with variables conditions loops
functions
lists tuples dictionaries and sets Those tools
are very useful but as a program
becomes larger we also need a way
to organize the code itself If everything
is placed inside one long script the
program can become difficult to read difficult
to test and difficult to update This
module introduces four important ideas The first
is a module A module is usually
one Python file that contains reusable code
The second is a package A package
groups related modules together The third is
a class A class is a blueprint
that combines related data and behavior The
fourth is an object An object is
one actual instance created from a class
The goal is not to become an
advanced software engineer in this module The
goal is much simpler I want you
to understand how Python projects can be
organized as they grow You will see
several executable Python examples throughout the
slides
When you reach a code slide you
can click the Run button below the
editor The first time you run Python
in the browser it may take a
few seconds for the Python environment to
load After that the code should run
more quickly As you move through the
module focus on the big idea behind
each example We want code that is
easier to reuse easier to understand and
easier to maintain